JAY RATHOD

Number: +971544349191

Email: jay4399@gmail.com **My Website:** www.jay4399.com

CV SUMMARY

Recently, I have worked with the Ministry of Education UAE for 2 Years. During my time, I have provided holistic education in Computer Science for copious students. I have also provided excellent teacher training for a year to several computer science teachers in the UAE. I have pursued my Bachelors in BSc Honours in Computer Science from University of Kent in UK. Then after, I pursued my Masters in MSc in Computer Science from University of Nottingham in UK achieving a First Class Honours and Distinction grades respectively.

Throughout my education and work experience, I have learnt, developed and nurtured numerous skills related to Computer Science and IT. My ambition was always to work in a global company that provides me with real responsibility so that I can truly feel like a valuable addition to the team.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

June 2018 - August 2020

Computer Science Teacher at MINISTRY OF EDUCATION (UAE)

- > Teaching students programming languages such as Python, HTML, CSS, C++ and JAVA.
- > Schooling students several theoretical concepts in Computer Science and Design Technology.
- ➤ Working with programs such as Fusion 360, Cisco Packet Tracer, LMS and Moodle.
- Assisted set up and delivering of distance e-learning to students during the COVID-19 pandemic.

September 2019 – August 2020 Computer Science Teacher Trainer at MINISTRY OF EDUCATION (UAE)

- > Trained several CS teachers on how to deliver lessons to students meritoriously by providing feedback.
- > Coached CS teachers on programming languages such as Python, HTML, CSS and Java.
- > Tutored CS teachers on several theoretical concepts related to IT and Computer Science.

RELEVANT SKILLS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Programming Languages

Excellent Knowledge: Python, Java, HTML/CSS and PHP.

(Built numerous programs and games using Python or Java. Built numerous websites using HTML/CSS)

➤ Intermediate Knowledge: SQL, C++ and JavaScript.

Other Skills and Achievements

- Worked on project based tasks in university utilising Agile, Waterfall, XP, PRINCE2 and Scrum Methodology.
- Wide knowledge on Networking based applications such as Cisco Packet Tracer and ONE Simulator.
- > Lead several team related projects that require programming through excellent leadership and communicative skills.
- Possess an excellent knowledge on MS Office applications such as Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Teams etc.
- Completed plentiful solo projects during my university education or for self-learning.
- I'm motivated, confident, always possess a readiness to learn, have the ability to listen and communicate effectively on anything/anyone I work on/with.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

2016 - 2017 University of Nottingham (UK) (Masters)

Degree: MSc in Computer Science

Final Grade: Distinction

Master's Dissertation Project: Refining Output Efficiency for VDTN Routing Protocols.

The dissertation project involved using The ONE Simulator for network simulation. The simulator would simulate a real life scenario of communication between several cars. I had programmed a new routing protocol to provide further efficiency to the interaction between them and several other elements.

2013 - 2016 University of Kent (UK) (Bachelors)

Degree: BSc Honors in Computer Science

Final Grade: First Class Honors

Year 3 Dissertation Project: Create Modern Art Using Human Brainwaves (Java)

The dissertation project involved using a person's brainwaves through which the program would detect their emotions and paint a picture accordingly. The EPOC headset would detect whether a person is sad, happy, frustrated, bored etc. and paint on a blank canvas reflecting their emotions. The project was the winner in the Project Fair held by several universities.

2011-2013 Good Shepherd International School (India) (International Baccalaureate Diploma)

Final Grade: 31 Points

2005-2011 Good Shepherd International School (India) (IGCSE)

Final Grade: **Distinction**

OTHER INFORMATION

Language Fluency: English (Excellent), Hindi (Excellent), French (Intermediate).

Hobbies: I love playing Basketball and keeping fit. I also believe strongly in self learning and love to browse websites like Codemy, Khan Academy, Coursera and acquire resourceful knowledge and practice on my programming skills. I also like to assist other students and teachers if they seek advice or help.

REFERENCES – Available on Request